Sylvia Davidson

sylviajp5@gmail.com

Contact: +91 9739140041

+91 9886510205

Summary A highly motivated individual having almost 4+ years of work experience within the Big 4 companies spanning areas of Strategy, Research and Transfer pricing. Aspiring to contribute qualitatively in areas of Business management, Management solutions, Research and insights for business development etc.

Professional History

Deloitte, Risk & Financial Advisory Services, Bangalore.

March 2022- September 2022

Strategy & Innovation

- Trends Sensing Radar- Worked on research and build-out of trending investments that the firm could prospectively look at/serve as a knowledge base for probable business implementation and use by general tech savvy readers.
- Research involved use of Deloitte's internal resource bases such as KX- Assets, Deloitte Insights, Tech trends, Cura etc to build out a comprehensive read on future tech trends that can profit the business.
- The repository was intended for the Leadsership's strategic planning and investment of cutting-edge technology for future business growth.
- Worked as a consultant with the S&I Investments team, on building out the quarterly reports of Tech Investments that Deloitte's Leadership invests in.
- Tracking, maintenance and updation of the Investment portfolio, facilitating daily tasks and to-dos.
- Helped in building out strategic questions for the stakeholder's decision on prospective Tech Investments.
- Preparation of Agenda and MoM for everyday calls with the Senior manager.

Internal Communications

- Worked on updating and refreshing the Diversity, Equity and Inclusion(DEI) page of Deloitte's Advisory practice(USI).
- Worked on connecting various stakeholders of the DEI page to gather inputs, plan, process information for the page along with other project management tactics to drive the project.

KPMG, Global Shared Services, Bangalore.

February 2012- July 2013

- Functional analysis of companies for the transfer pricing report mainly for US based projects, Ireland and Indian regions.
- Benchmarking analysis which includes running of searches on databases mostly on Amadeus and Oriana based on region specifications.
- Preparation of the elimination charts for the review of trade descriptions and the Internet reviews. Preparation of the Financial (PLI) summary based on the functions performed and concluding it with the region specific search- write up.
- Preparation of Industry write- ups based on the region specific formats and requirements.

Ernst and Young, GSS, Bangalore.

May 2010- August 2011

- Prepared functional analysis of companies for the transfer pricing reports
- Functional analysis includes running of searches on databases like Global fusion, Amadeus and Oriana based on the specifications.
- Preparation of the elimination charts for the review of trade descriptions, Internet reviews, financial (PLI) summaries, search- write ups etc.
- Handled and analyzed agreement reviews and preparation of restatements.

Additional Work Experience

Sellerapp Private Limited, Bangalore

Content Writer- Technical

February- March 2023

- Worked on creating content for Blogs, Backlinks, Re- write articles and Help articles for sellers as part of Sellerapp's package of B2B SaaS services for Amazon.
- Gained insights into Keyword strategy, Content marketing and SEO Marketing.
- Worked and produced 3 backlink articles in a month, involving key deep dive research into E- commerce businesses and platforms, Keyword strategizing, SEO strategy for product listings etc.

Educational History

• Post Graduate Diploma in Business Administration (2008-2010).

Specialization- Finance and Banking & Insurance

Mount Carmel Institute of Management, Bangalore

• Bachelor of Business Management (2005-2008)

Specialization - Finance

Mount Carmel College, Bangalore

- **Pre- university course** from Mount Carmel College, (2003-2005), Bangalore
- Standard 10 of the Karnataka State Secondary School leaving Certificate (SSLC) Board Stella Maris School, Bangalore.

Internships

Post Graduate Level (PGDBA- 2nd Semester 2009)

Organization: ING Life Insurance

Project title: A study on Portfolio Management

Responsibilities: Interned as a corporate channel agent

Duration: 2 months

Post Graduate Level (PGDBA- 4th Semester 2010)

Organization: Catalyst Management Services

Project title: A study on Improvement of Cost efficiency

Duration: 2 months

Skills and Other activities

- Enrolled with Christ University in an MPhil program in Marketing to keep up with learning activities in the year 2019.
- Strong communications and analytical skills, capable of liaising with different teams. Certification on Personal
 excellence and Power-A Personality development Course that enhances oratory skills, stage management and event
 management skills.
- Certification in French and Spanish- basic level
- Represented the Institute (Mount Carmel Management Institute) in the marketing event at IBS

 ICFAI Hyderabad and SDM Mysore in the year 2008.
- Member of the editorial team of LUMINOS- the annual magazine of Mount Carmel Institute of Management for the years 2009 and 2010
- Member of the editorial team of "The Proclamation:- the youth magazine of St James Church for 2 consecutive years(2009-2011)

• Elected as the General Secretary to the student council at MCIM for the year 2009-10.